<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Dan De Sousa's Blog</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://dandesousa.com/feeds/Technology.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://dandesousa.com/</id><updated>2012-12-09T20:07:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Linking Together iCloud, Photo Stream and Dropbox.</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/linking-together-icloud-photo-stream-and-dropbox.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-09T20:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2012-12-09:linking-together-icloud-photo-stream-and-dropbox.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking for a way to link together iCloud and Dropbox to manage your
photos? Look no further; the following is a guide to getting your iOS
and Photo Stream photos automatically into Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/dropbx-300x300.png" title="dropbx" /&gt; &lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/icloud-300x297.jpg" title="icloud" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This  process started because I was looking for a way to manage all my
photos on my iPad. I want to take pictures with my DSLR or point and
shoot, download them to my iPad with the camera connection kit, and have
them automatically added to my cloud or local photo library.
Unfortunately many of the photo management services on the iPad are
lacking, and it is not easy to create and sync albums through iCloud.
What I really wanted was a permanent backup solution for photos on my
iPad. It would also be nice to be able to manage my photos with a third
party application like Picasa. That's when I thought to use Photo Stream
as a delivery mechanism to upload photos to Dropbox. I trust Dropbox to
keep my photos safe, and I like having access to all my photos on all my
devices. Of course, all these photos are going to take up a lot of space
over time. I cover the costs of this setup in the last section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup will work on Windows or Mac, but I'll go over the
instructions for Windows. If there are requests I can post directions
for OS X, though it should be pretty straightforward from the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need these applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/dl1455"&gt;iCloud Control Panel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These instructions have you setup iCloud Control Panel to download your
Photo Stream uploaded photos (which includes all photos added to your
iOS through either the camera app or the camera connection kit) a
Dropbox folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you'll want to make sure Dropbox is configured and setup for your
account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second after you install the iCloud Control Panel, you want to find it
under Control Panel &gt; iCloud. You should see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/icloudcontrolpanel.png" title="icloudcontrolpanel" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select options next to Photo Stream:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/options.png" title="options" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that "My Photo Stream" is selected. Also check "Shared Photo
Streams" if you use that feature. Select "Change" next to "Photo Stream
location" and navigate to your Dropbox directory. You can either select
the Photos directory. In the follow example I've created a dedicated
directory just for my Photo Stream photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/files.png" title="files" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry about the directories under "Photo Streams" they will appear
once your computer starts download photos from Apple. Once it's
selected, select "OK" all the way until you get back to the main control
panel window and close it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on, all new pictures on your iOS device will automatically be
downloaded to your local machine, and since the location of the download
is in Dropbox, it will be uploaded to your Dropbox account as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be asking why go through to the trouble of doing this. Well
there are a number of benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can access all your photos on all your devices, computers and on
    the web securely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage your photo library solely from your iPad, iPhone with Dropbox
    and the Photos app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freedom to delete old photos from your iOS device without fear that
    they will disappear from iCloud after 30 days or when your 1000
    photo limit is reached. If dropbox is installed on your iOS device,
    you can even view them there long after they've disappeared from
    Photo Stream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically download photos to all your computers at once (as long
    as your computer with iCloud Control Panel is running)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically upload photos to all your iOS devices from any
    computer in the world or the web by dropping them in the Photo
    Stream &gt; Uploads folder (as long as your iCloud Control Panel
    computer is running)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Own" all your photos, organize them into albums and make them
    accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Long Term Costs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup does not come without its costs. While iCloud and Photo
Stream are free for Photos, a new dropbox free user probably doesn't
have much room to be storing their entire photo library. In the long
term this will like depend on having a paid account. However, fret not,
since Dropbox is always running a number of promotions to increase
available space. The biggest is the &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/spacerace"&gt;Dropbox Space Race&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/help/category/Referrals"&gt;referral
program&lt;/a&gt;. You can also &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/pricing"&gt;Dropbox's pricing details&lt;/a&gt; which have
recently expanded. Furthermore, with the decrease in price of storage,
we should see costs come down and capacity go up in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to comment or suggest alternate setups. So far this has
been working quite well and allowing me to leverage the best of both of
these great cloud services.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dropbox"></category><category term="icloud"></category><category term="photo stream"></category></entry><entry><title>Changing PlexSync Temporary Directory</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/changing-plexsync-temporary-directory.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-20T20:10:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2012-11-20:changing-plexsync-temporary-directory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Plex just announced a great new syncing feature for iOS devices, but I
noticed that when I started syncing, my SSD would quickly fill up. It
turns out that as of the current release of plex server v0.9.7.3, you
cannot directly change the directory. However, you can change the entire
local application path for plex. There are instructions on the Plex wiki
detailing how this is done:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.plexapp.com/index.php/Plex_Media_Server_Preferences#Advanced_Preferences%20%20"&gt;Plex Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case I set LocalAppDataPath in the registry to my RAID disc which
has plenty of storage. You'll have to follow the instructions for your
particular platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: &lt;/strong&gt;Make sure that when you change the path you copy your old
plex app data directory to preserve all your metadata, thumbnails, and
database. On Windows, its in "C:/Users/\&amp;lt;USERNAME&gt;/AppData/Local/Plex
Media Server". Also important, remember that the directory
Cache/Transcode/Sync &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; exist. I tried to delete the cache to save
myself some transfer time and when I was missing that
Cache/Transcode/Sync directory, PlexSync would not work at all. Once I
restored the directory, all was well.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plex"></category></entry><entry><title>HowTo: Setup a network with two internet connections</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/howto-setup-a-network-with-two-internet-connections.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-26T08:41:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2012-05-26:howto-setup-a-network-with-two-internet-connections.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are living in an area where internet connection options are
limited, you may find yourself in a connundrum. Perhaps you want to be
able to use high bandwidth services (netflix, itunes, bittorrent,
gaming) but a single connection pipe is not large enough to accomodate
all the traffic. Or perhaps, your internet is capped or throttled after
a certain amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Situation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
I currently live in such an area, where my faster internet provider will
quickly throttle for high usage. I needed to be able to download (iTunes
videos, Steam games, etc), but my primary provider throttles if we
download too much. To make matters worse, my girlfriend works from home,
so she needs a fast constant connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I wanted was to be able to use Clear (which has great speed and
reception in our area) for normal internet and DSL for all the high
bandwidth content. We needed to have one or two computers in our network
use the DSL, and the others use Clear. However, we still needed everyone
on the same network because we needed to access file shares and other
applications running on the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much searching I found a solution that fits my needs and that I
hope will help some other people as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The solution to my problem is to create a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple Gateway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; setup.
The idea is you have a standard network with one internet connection
that acts as the primary gateway. By default all connecting devices use
this connection. You then add one or more routers with separate incoming
connections as other gateways. You assign them IPs and you tell the
devices you want to use that gateway and it will use it for those
connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So in summary, this setup will allow you to keep all devices on one
network and manually assign which connection each device uses (using one
connection as the default).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just need to follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup your default gateway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For the purpose of this article, gateway is just another term for a
router with an incoming WAN or internet connection. Chances are your
default gateway is already setup -- its just your current single
connection network setup. If you want to continue to use this connection
as the default for all devices on the network, leave as is and continue
to the next step. Otherwise swap the internet connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The internet connection on this gateway will be used for all devices by
default.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make a note of your router's IP address; in most cases it is
'192.168.1.1'.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also note the DHCP range of your router, this varies by model but on the
common dd-wrt setup can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/default-gateway-192.168.1.1-dhcp-address-781x1024.png" title="default-gateway-192.168.1.1-dhcp-address" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For this scenario our DHCP range starts at 192.168.1.100. So anything
from 192.168.1.0 - 192.168.1.99 is out of range and won't be used by the
router when assigning the addresses to devices. This is important to
know for the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup your second gateway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
You want to setup a completely separate network with the second router
and connection. Don't connect the second gateway to the main network
yet. Verify that on your second connection you have an internet
connection and everything is working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assign the second gateway an IP address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that works, you want to give the second gateway a different IP
address to distinguish it from the primary gateway. Since the primary
gateway is IP address 192.168.1.1, we'll use 192.168.1.2. Note that the
address must be outside the range of DHCP for the primary gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable DHCP on the second gateway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you want to disable DHCP server on the second gateway. If you are
using DD-WRT, the highlighted radio box in the box image should be
'Disable'. This is important, DHCP MUST BE DISABLED. Not set to a new
gateway, not turned onto DHCP forwarding -- DISABLED. Make sure you hit
apply and save any settings before moving onto the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect your second gateway to your network through the LAN port&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Now connect your second gateway to your network through the LAN part as
you would connect a switch to your network to allow for additional
connections. Once you do so, you should be able to connect to your
primary network and access both the primary gateway and the secondary
gateway by their addresses. Confirm this by ensuring you can access
192.168.1.1 and 192.168.1.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure your machines to use the alternative gateway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Good news is you are pretty much done now. You can confirm your setup is
working by assigning a machine to either network. You want to open up
your network menu and find your network interface (representing the one
connected to your network  -- be it wired or wireless).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/network-1.png" title="network-1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;now right click and select properties. Then select the IPv4 settings and
hit properties again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/network-2.png" title="network-2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you want to manually configure your connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/network-3.png" title="network-3" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your IP address, assign anything that is outside the DHCP range of
your router (anything below 192.168.1.100 works in this example). Leave
subnet mask matching your primary gateway and assign default gateway to
the second connection. You'll also want to add that as the DNS server.
This tells this network interface to use that gateway for your internet
connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all works successfully you should now have access, and all traffic on
that box will flow to your second gateway, leaving your other
connections unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most devices give you the ability to customize the your IP configuration
this way, so you should be able to configure your devices in any manner
you choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repeat for any additional connections &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The multiple gateway setup works for as many connections as you want.
Just continue adding addresses outside your DHCP range for your gateways
and you should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this will be useful to people out there trying to work out how
to use multiple connections in their home network. I know it was for me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="networking"></category></entry><entry><title>HowTo Fix: MacBook Pro and Dell 2711 DisplayPort Issues</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/howto-fix-macbook-pro-and-dell-2711-displayport-issues.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-07T21:41:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2012-03-07:howto-fix-macbook-pro-and-dell-2711-displayport-issues.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I chose to get the Dell U2711 mostly due to PC compatibility and price
advantages over the Cinema Display. However, having a MacBook Pro I
wanted to also connect it to  my nice display. I ordered a
Mini-DisplayPort to DisplayPort cable and all worked fine until one day
it didn't. The screen was black and no signal was being delivered
between my MacBook Pro and the display. I tested with my girlfriend's
computer and the problem persisted. I ordered yet another cable and the
problem still persisted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew something was wrong with the display. Finally I solved my problem
in the most simple way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While the monitor was on, I pulled the U2711's power cable and waited
about 15-30 seconds. I plugged the monitor back in and switch to
DisplayPort and it worked perfected!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously something is wrong with Dell's monitor in this instance, but
this simple fix should help everyone having headaches with this like me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="apple"></category><category term="macbook pro"></category><category term="dell"></category><category term="displayport"></category><category term="u2711"></category></entry><entry><title>HowTo Fix: Slow SSD Boot Times in Mac OS X</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/howto-fix-slow-ssd-boot-times-in-mac-os-x.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-07T21:31:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2012-03-07:howto-fix-slow-ssd-boot-times-in-mac-os-x.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently bought a ssd for my macbook pro and noticed after installing
and reformatting, the boot times were slow ... about as slow as my hdd
or even slower. If you have an SSD, you can except boot times around 15
seconds or so. If you are encountering boot times of 35+ seconds, you
may have the same problem I had. I was able to solve the problem by
following these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System Preferences -&gt; Startup Disk. Make sure that your SSD drive
    is selected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Disk Utility and select your drive, and click "Repair Disk
    Permissions"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht1379"&gt;Reset your PRAM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3964"&gt;Reset your SMC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The final step of reseting the SMC finally fixed this for me, but I had
tried all the steps before hand, so I cannot be sure which will work for
you. If you have any comments, please post for the benefit of all
readers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ssd"></category><category term="apple"></category><category term="macbook"></category><category term="boot"></category></entry><entry><title>The Ultimate Home Media Center Solution [Spoiler: Plex!]</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/the-ultimate-home-media-center-solution-spoiler-plex.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-05T23:08:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2011-11-05:the-ultimate-home-media-center-solution-spoiler-plex.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this article, I cover my opinion on currently the best media center
option for managing local content libraries, and my thoughts on the
state of digital video distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not condone any mention of piracy in the article and any references
are merely for illustrative purposes regarding this rather opinionated
article :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to jump ahead to the guide, but first some background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I Discovered Plex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
I can say that I have been searching for the "perfect" home media center
for a long time. I have a rather large collection of TV Shows and DVDs
that have been ripped. For years I struggled with getting that media on
devices I wanted. At first I converted them to PS3 compatible formats
and streamed them over DLNA using TwonkeyMedia. That was great except
that conversions took a long time. Then if I wanted them on my iPhone or
iPod I need to convert them yet again, to a different format. Then I
needed space for all those duplicate files (and managing them was a
nightmare). There seemed to be a lot of disjoint solutions which
required manual management. A friend of mine suggested XBMC, which is a
great home media center front end with tons of plug-in support. It
actually eventually led to my discovery of what I believe to be clearly
the best product out there for managing a local collection of content
and getting it on your devices, and it is called &lt;a href="http://www.plexapp.com/"&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is Plex?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
First, let me explain what Plex does. Plex is a media center front end
for Plex Media Server. Basically, Plex Media Server manages a library of
media on a computer for you, and serves it up to multiple devices. So
you can have a drive with all your TV Shows, Movies, Music, Photos, etc
and Plex Media Server (PMS -- an unfortunate abbreviation) will deliver
it over your home network or the internet. Plex is a UI which runs on a
computer, mobile phone or TV and gives you access to that content. It
looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/episode_overview.png" title="episode_overview" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./static/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/episode_overview.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Basically gives you all your episodes (with metadata) automatically.
Lets you browse by tons of different categories, like unwatched or
recently aired/added. Did I mention it automatically organize your media
assuming you have everything reasonable named? Basically it is pretty
close to media center nirvana, and the basic application and server are
free to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what makes this better than any other solution out there, especially
XBMC (from which Plex was originally development from)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it's all about Plex Media Server. Basically you can setup one
machine in your network with media center, and serve up content to every
client device running plex. The Plex client is available for Mac, Roku,
Samsung and LG TVs, and jailbroken Apple TVs and more -- so theres
plenty of choice on the set top box front. Additionally there are native
iPhone, iPad, and Android apps. Also, Plex Media Server automatically
live transcodes videos which are unsupported on client devices, and
almost all video formats are supported. This solves the problem I had
originally in storing many copies of files. Also, since everything is on
a common server, you can stop a show or movie on your TV, then watch it
on your iPad in bed. The server keeps track of partially watch shows on
all devices. Also, you may want to search for an application called
sickbeard, as it can integrate with plex to enhance your experience
(that is all I can say :-) ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like what you hear, I suggest trying it out. I can also recommend
a setup which I've found useful, not everyone needs what I have, you can
make due with less, but my setup fits with my other server needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting Up Plex Media Center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
EDIT: I just noticed that as of the latest update, Plex is also
available for Windows. So you can use any machine you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You Will Need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac Mini (Alternative: Samsung or LG TV with Apps, Roku, Google TV,
    Apple TV)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated Server of any OS (Mac Mini will do, or any other machine
    so long as it is on while you watch videos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plex for iOS / Android (Last I checked it was about \$3-5 in the app
    store but definitely the best purchase I've made)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plex for Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plex Media Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
Rough Setup and Reasoning:

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

1.  First, you want to setup your Mac Mini or other plex box. I
    recommend a mac mini because it is small and provides the best
    looking, fastest Plex experience. You also get a complete client
    implementation. It is also the most expensive option. There are Plex
    clients for TVs, Roku, Google TV or Apple TV (jailbroken), so you
    can also try one of those if you already have a different box.
2.  You should install and run Plex Media Server on a dedicated box you
    can always count on being on when you want to watch videos. This
    should also be the server all the media is stored on. Advantage of
    an always on server is that you can access your content from any
    time on the network (or on the internet if you setup myPlex which is
    available as of Plex 0.9.5).
3.  Plex for iOS is only necessary if you want to watch you media on
    mobile devices. The apps cost a few bucks but they are totally worth
    it and highly polished.
4.  Once you setup PMS you just need to run plex and it should
    auto-detect your local server, exposing all your media. If you run
    an alternative plex client you may need to point it to the address
    of your server.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why People Want Plex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked myself why people want home media centers. I don't think it is
necessarily due to wanting to own copies of movies, tv shows and music.
I think that Plex and XBMC have succeeded because simply put, the
providers and TV device manufacturers have failed consumers. There is no
single product out there that can give you everything you want, despite
having tons of companies dedicated to this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Netflix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix is cheap and great, but it has a terrible selection. I mean 8\$
a month isn't much but it seems like half the content on there are
national geographic documentaries. They have great coverage for client
devices (all mobile phone platforms, tablets, set tops, tvs) but their
coverage is just so spotty. It seems like they are always losing
providers or having content negotiation problems. Even so, most shows
only come out on Netflix the same time they come out on DVD. Maybe I
don't want to wait 8 months to watch a TV show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon Instant Video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next best service is probably Amazon Instant Video. It has a decent
selection of TV shows and if you are an Amazon Prime member, the deal is
great (I recently get addicted to Doctor Who thanks to Amazon Instant
Video and am now I lover of the series). The problem with Amazon is that
the client support is simply abysmal. I don't understand what they are
doing. Amazon is perhaps my favorite internet company but I think
whoever is running their video distribution strategy is a buffoon.
Amazon Instant Video has clients for Roku and some TVs. However, theres
no iOS support (no iPad -- come on!), no Android support, no apple tv
support. If you sell a streaming service you need to make it accessible.
Also, same criticism applies to the waiting period as netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iTunes and Apple TV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple TV provides a wide selection of TV Shows and Movies. They have
their own dedicated box which is simple and cheap. Unfortunately, Apple
TV has serious, serious flaws. The deal breaker being that its 720p, as
is most of the content on the iTunes store. Also, theres no subscription
option, you have to actually buy all the episodes of every show. Its
almost a good alternative if you don't want cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what the world really needs is a digital form of on demand
cable. Where you choose your box or client, and subscribe through a
cable provider to certain shows or subsets of channels and have
optionally commercial free streaming of content. Then you have access to
all their networks contents from all time. The issue is that content
providers and cable companies don't want to stray from a profitable
traditional business model. They like charging you 100\$ a month for
digital cable, when you watch about 25% of the shows and channels. Then
they want to sell people box set DVDs they will watch once if ever after
the original airing date. They think this is the best way to make money.
What they don't realize is that if they provide customers with choice,
such as choosing which channels they watch, choosing whether or not to
watch with commercials, they will make more money. You can lend a box
set of DVDs to your friend. You can't share DRM digital rental,
subscription or purchase, and you can't resell it when you are finish
(this is why the video game industry loves digital downloads -- they
lose millions to the resale game market). This is not even to mention
the possibility for targeted advertisements or exposing people to shows
directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does Plex solve this? Well let's be honest, a large number of
people who want XBMC or Plex are downloading TV Shows or ripping their
own bought discs. They are making this complete service for themselves,
for the subset of shows they want to watch. The sad thing is that the
piracy is actually a better solution then what is legally available.
Using the right tools, it can become completely automated, commercial
free, and instant available after airing -- you could get full quality
720 TV shows and 1080p Movies as soon as they air or become commercially
available without lifting a finger. Get with the program providers, if
people are willing to spend thousands on custom servers, software and
services, they will pay a little extra for complete, high quality
streaming access that is guaranteed and legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully Google, Microsoft or Apple will get their act together and
release a good solution. Apple has a good track record with provider
industries in getting content on digital devices. Maybe we will see an
Apple TV running iOS with native third party app support soon. That
could mean an app store that supports channels from providers, or a
common subscription model. There is a lot of money to be made here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd like to hear what anyone else thinks. What sort of setup do you guys
have, what do you want to see in a streaming service that doesn't exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plex"></category><category term="home media center"></category></entry><entry><title>Realtek RTL8111 Windows Server 2008</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/realtek-rtl8111-windows-server-2008.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-03T21:45:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2011-06-03:realtek-rtl8111-windows-server-2008.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Encountered an issue when loading Windows Server 2008 R2 onto my new
media server. Seems it couldn't find my Realtek Gigabit onboard NIC on
my Biostar A880G+. Anyway after much searching I failure installing the
official realtek driver. I found the following driver which worked and
allowed me to update all my other drivers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://drivers.softpedia.com/progDownload/Realtek-RTL8110SC-L-Driver-6218-for-WinServer-2008-Download-77885.html"&gt;http://drivers.softpedia.com/progDownload/Realtek-RTL8110SC-L-Driver-6218-for-WinServer-2008-Download-77885.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Getting Highpoint RocketRaid 2640x4 Controller To Work In Linux</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/getting-highpoint-rocketraid-2640x4-controller-to-work-in-linux.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-03T17:29:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2011-06-03:getting-highpoint-rocketraid-2640x4-controller-to-work-in-linux.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I finally got around to re-organizing my home server situation, and
was given a RocketRaid 2640x4 SAS Raid Controller from a friend. My
intention was to simply use it for the extra SATA slots and not bother
with its own on-board RAID. However, when I tried to get it to work, I
noticed that the drives weren't being detected under Ubuntu. I scored
the internet until I finally found a post from a newegg buyer that
resolved my issue and I feel its important enough to post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps you need to follow to get this controller to work
under Linux. They may work for all versions of Linux but I have not
tried them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.) Flash the BIOS to legacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't need the RAID features, you can flash the BIOS on the card
to replace the current BIOS with a legacy BIOS &lt;em&gt;sans&lt;/em&gt; RAID. To do this,
simply download the legacy BIOS from the Highpoint website. You can then
either run the highpoint flash utility under windows or you'll need to
create a DOS boot disk. If you have access to a Windows box, using the
utility is the easier course of action. When you extract the BIOS zip it
should be listed as hptflash.exe and look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./static/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Capture-300x178.png" title="Capture" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.) Configure the drive to be under legacy mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now plug you card back into the linux box and make sure that all the
drives connected to the card are listed as "legacy" in the RocketRaid
RAID utility that appears when you boot your machine (You may need to
press CTRL+H when the appropriate screen appears).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.) Download and Compile the Driver Source&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you need to make sure the drivers are properly installed. I got
issues when I tried to install the pre-built binaries. Luckily its
pretty easy to compile the drivers yourself. Simply download the
&lt;em&gt;legacy&lt;/em&gt; drives from the RocketRaid site on the same page as the BIOS.
Now just cd in the lowest level of the source directory and type "sudo
make install". You'll see it build and then you are done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drivers will then be installed. If you reboot and check ls /dev you
should see a drive labeled sd\&amp;lt;*&gt; for every drive connect to the card
or your motherboard. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>HTPC Stutter Over HDMI on Samsung HDTV</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/htpc-stutter-over-hdmi-on-samsung-hdtv.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-18T23:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2011-02-18:htpc-stutter-over-hdmi-on-samsung-hdtv.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This will be a quick one. I recently built an HTPC to run XBMC and play
videos off my file share. I noticed that almost all videos had
an occasional stutter that would occur every few seconds and produce a
very slight stutter in the image. This happened for all file types and
resolutions. I'm running with an integrated ATI HD 4250.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually figured out that it was my TV settings. I was connecting
over HDMI and Samsung must do some extra processing or handshaking over
the HDMI to HTPC. I realized this since I connected my HTPC to my
monitor at the same resolution (1080p 60hz) and I experienced perfect
video playback. I eventually was able to solve the problem by setting
the HDMI input source name to PC and disabling Auto Motion Plus
features. It seems like this tells the Samsung set to stop any extra
processing that causes and occasional stutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps someone out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I found that turning off "de-interlacing" in the ATI catalyst
settings eliminated this effect. Try that in addition to the above steps&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hdmi"></category><category term="samsung"></category><category term="tv"></category><category term="xbmc"></category></entry><entry><title>HowTo Fix: iOS 4.3 Beta Installed on iPad but Missing Gestures</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/howto-fix-ios-43-beta-installed-on-ipad-but-missing-gestures.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-15T21:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2011-01-15:howto-fix-ios-43-beta-installed-on-ipad-but-missing-gestures.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently installed the iPad OS 4.3 beta and found that the gestures
were missing. A bit of tinkering around and I realized that actually I
had not yet turned on my iPad for development use (something required to
access these new features). If you are experiencing the same problems,
following these steps to enabled gestures on your iPad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that gestures are not enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plug you iPad into your mac and bring up the xcode organizer and
    click "enable development use" on your iPad's summary screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kill and restart the settings app on your iPad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm you now have gestures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>HowTo Fix: C# .NET BackgroundWorker.IsBusy Always True</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/howto-fix-c-net-backgroundworkerisbusy-always-true.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-20T23:52:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2010-08-20:howto-fix-c-net-backgroundworkerisbusy-always-true.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;BackgroundWorker provides a great simplified mechanism for seperating
CPU intensive work from the UI thread in C# .NET. Indeed&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.componentmodel.backgroundworker.aspx"&gt;the MSDN
documentation does an excellent job detailing its usage&lt;/a&gt;. However, you
may come across a bug wherein you need to run the backgroundworker while
it is still running. You have code like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ComponentModel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;BackgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;backgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;someEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;backgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;IsBusy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;Thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Yield&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;backgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;RunWorkerAsync&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But you may find that backgroundWorker.IsBusy is always true so the loop
never executes. It seems that simply yielding the thread will not force
the backgroundWorker to mark itself as done even though that worker
thread has successfully completed. In some situations you are blocking
the UI so it cannot mark itself complete. To resolve the problem, simply
include a call to System.Windows.Forms.Application.DoEvents(). You can
do this even if you are running an application under WPF. It should
force the UI to load a frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Windows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Forms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ComponentModel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;BackgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;backgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;someEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;backgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;IsBusy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;Thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Yield&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;Application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;DoEvents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;backgroundWorker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;RunWorkerAsync&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For more information on this method check out &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.windows.forms.application.doevents.aspx"&gt;the MSDN documentation on
Application.DoEvents()&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=".net"></category><category term="C#"></category><category term="Threading"></category></entry><entry><title>HowTo Fix: Roomba Clicking Noise</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/howto-fix-roomba-clicking-noise.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-28T13:02:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2010-05-28:howto-fix-roomba-clicking-noise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back the vacuum in our apartment stopped working so I decided to
do something I always wanted: Get a roomba. So far its been great and it
keeps the carpet clean with minimum effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we have encountered some problems where the Roomba occasionally
makes a repeated clicking noise and then shuts off. It then repeats
"Please Clean Roomba's Brushes". It got to the point where it was making
the clicking noise EVERY time it was run and would shut down after about
2 minutes. I tried reseting the battery, cleaning the
brushes...everything. Finally I realized what was wrong. I wasn't
cleaning the brushes properly. If you have a lot of dirt in your carpet
or pets (we have cats), it's easy for fibers to get wrapped around some
of the moving parts of the roomba brush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to fix the problem simply remove the brushes from the Roomba as your
normally would to clean them. However, check under the yellow cap at the
end of both brushes (by that I mean the brush and the rubber roller).
Don't worry, they are designed to come off, so you can pull on them.
Afterwards you may see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4045/4647414023_625bc72f44_d.jpg" title="Roomba Brush Under-Cap" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just pull out all the hair and fibers with a pencil or paper clip and
replace the yellow cap. Afterwards your roomba will be good as new! Be
aware though, that this is likely to happen again so make sure you
periodically clean under the cap of both brush attachments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4038/4647413667_40a50cb12a_d.jpg" title="Another Brush Angle" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cleaning"></category><category term="robots"></category><category term="roomba"></category></entry><entry><title>Quick Fix: iPhone Microphone and Headset Buttons don’t work</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/quick-fix-iphone-microphone-and-headset-buttons-dont-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-04T14:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2010-04-04:quick-fix-iphone-microphone-and-headset-buttons-dont-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently had a problem with my iPhone headphones where neither the
built in mic nor the headphone answer (or start/stop) button would work.
I attributed the failure to a recent tumble which also crack my front
glass along the bezel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, thanks to a helpful blog post I was able to correct the problem.
Seems like a rather large piece lint had made it's way into the
headphone jack and was blocking the plug. I would have never figured it
out if it wasn't for this helpful blog post. So I've linked it below and
will leave the explanation to him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.iphoneincanada.ca/tips-tricks/how-to-fix-your-iphone-headphones-mic-if-its-not-working/&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="iphone"></category></entry><entry><title>How To: Dual Monitors in Ubuntu with Nvidia</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/how-to-dual-monitors-in-ubuntu-with-nvidia.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-24T15:13:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2010-01-24:how-to-dual-monitors-in-ubuntu-with-nvidia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I noticed that a lot of people are getting "cannot parse xorg.conf"
message when they try to set up dual monitors with Nvidia settings
manager in ubuntu. Here is the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the command line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    sudo nvidia-xconfig

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see it tell you that it overrode your xorg.conf. If you get
warnings don't worry, it's likely just indicating that there was a
previous problem. Then on the command line again, type this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    sudo nvidia-settings

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now setup your dual monitor or triple monitor configuration as you want
(with Twin View and the correct orientation). Then hit save
configuration at the bottom and you should see that you get no error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reboot and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux"></category></entry><entry><title>HF100 + ImageMixer Fix For Startup Freeze</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/hf100-imagemixer-fix-for-startup-freeze.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-06T17:23:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2009-02-06:hf100-imagemixer-fix-for-startup-freeze.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I just got a new camcorder thanks to now qualifying for the US
stimulus package from back in April. I was looking around for something
to help stimulate the economy and decided that I should get a camcorder
while prices are low and money is high. Anyway, the HF100 is flash based
and really nice. It records in full HD 1080p with pretty decent picture
quality, though I have yet to record in full light setting (outside). So
far I only have sort of dim shots indoors of my roommate's cats and my
ferret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway in my commitment to making a post with something useful every
week, I've decided to share a tip with the world. Seems as though when I
installed my ImageMixer 3 SE software, it would just freeze upon
startup. Normally I wouldn't mind the issue with crap proprietary
software, but there is no easy way to edit .MTS/M2TS files without
converting and losing quality. Since I prefer to keep the originals as
well as edit them so that extra footage is chopped off, I needed to
figure out what was wrong. After some digging I found the solution to my
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this occurs for you, you need to install all third party codec packs
you installed. I had the CCCP (Community Codec Pak), which is useful for
watching MKVs. Unfortunately, that was messing up something, so I had to
uninstall it. I found numerous posts talking about uninstalling codec
packs, so that's probably the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that eliminates the ability to play back MKV's in WMV. I
don't have a solution for this but I suggest installing &lt;a href="http://www.videolan.org/vlc/"&gt;VLC&lt;/a&gt;. It is
wonderful and plays everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first video, the high definition is better if you go straight to
youtube:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/eBXqOGTKyaA&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" width="480" height="295" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always"&gt;
&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="canon"></category><category term="hf100"></category><category term="imagemixer"></category></entry><entry><title>NES ROM Editing</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/nes-rom-editing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-12T12:39:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2008-11-12:nes-rom-editing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I did a presentation a couple years ago on NES Rom editting and I
learned a lot about how to do some simple rom hacking and how old school
cheat tools like game genie and game shark worked. Anyway I've decided
to share the presentation I gave as well as all the resources I used.
Everything is totally open. Everything I used to make the presentation
below is included in the zip file and I even wrote up a quick little
tool in .NET to translate text to dragon warrior tile entries. Anyway
feel free to edit it as much as you'd like, but if you do anything cool
with it I'd like to know so just shoot me an e-mail or leave some info
in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cs.drexel.edu/~dsd33/demos/nes_rom_editting/Presentation.zip"&gt;Click here to download resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://docs.google.com/EmbedSlideshow?docid=d9jph9x_54gg9bdtcr" frameborder="0" width="410" height="342"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Me and the GOP</title><link href="http://dandesousa.com/me-and-the-gop.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-29T21:51:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:dandesousa.com,2008-10-29:me-and-the-gop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So contrary to my better judgement I've decided to post an old video of
myself at the GOP convention back in the day. I remember I was a big
Republican, back when I really just wanted to be different than my
parents and I was told that abortion was murder. Anyway one good thing
that came from this was that I did a "mock" news reporting for the GOP
convention. Yes this is me in 2000, when I was about 12ish. I was
probably just about to turn 13. Anyway, hopefully you'll get a kick out
of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/ZSIN4OAUyzU&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" width="425" height="344" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always"&gt;
&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GOP"></category><category term="Me"></category><category term="Politics"></category><category term="Republicans"></category></entry></feed>